Kyrsten Greenfield

New York, NY **678.925.4770**

kyrstengreenfield@hotmail.com www.kgreenfield.com

SUMMARY: Kyrsten is a Sr. UX Manager with dual degrees in Computer Science and Psychology and 10+ years of leading and supporting UX design and research efforts as a "player-coach". Her strongest skill sets include:

- Driving company-wide design and research efforts with significant impacts on profitability and products
- Managing team and project performance by tracking progress, evaluating metrics, and measuring outcomes
- Collaborating cross-functionally with leadership, colleagues, and clients to adapt and innovate

EXPERIENCE

SmartAsset — June 2017 - June 2023

Associate Director of UX / UX Manager (Sep 2021 - June 2023)

- Oversaw UX strategy, operations, and team leadership, resulting in significant revenue growth. Key accomplishments include:
 - Enhancing UX efficiency by introducing a design system, design standards, and handoff guidelines
 - Utilizing user-centric research methods to inform product development and decision-making across the organization
 - Coordinating with cross-functional leadership to align design and research initiatives with company objectives
 - Managing daily UX operations, involving team KPI development, hiring, onboarding, and mentoring
- Spearheaded large-scale end-to-end research initiatives that improved the consumer experience and drove unprecedented growth
- Drove strategic efforts to optimize core consumer experience, directly increasing monthly revenue by \$1m+

Senior UX Researcher (Sep 2019 - Sept 2021)

- Promoted to lead all end-to-end research initiatives in order to identify unmet product and consumer opportunities
- Developed research strategy aligning product goals with user and market demands
- Fostered a user-centric culture by organizing internal workshops and facilitating knowledge sharing and product feedback
- Advanced data-driven decision making by implementing a comprehensive framework to track user sentiment and satisfaction

UX Researcher (June 2017 - Sept 2019)

- Founded the UX research function at Unicorn-trajectory startup
- Oversaw company-wide market trend and consumer research efforts
- Transformed qualitative and quantitative data into actionable insights, influencing design and product strategies
- Led research and redesign initiative for an interactive web tool, improving clicks per user by 54% and SERP position from 19th to 4th

University of Georgia — Aug 2014 - Jan 2016

Research Assistant

- Conducted statistical analysis to enhance research operations
- Implemented new technologies (SPSS and JMP) to streamline and improve analytical procedures

Georgia Institute of Technology — May 2013 - May 2014

Undergraduate Researcher

 Improved research operations through cloud migration, increasing efficiency and bolstering participant privacy

EDUCATION

Georgia Institute of Technology BS, Computer Science (2016)

Georgia Institute of Technology BS, Psychology (2014)

CERTIFICATIONS

LifeLabs
CORE Management Training

SKILLS

UX Leadership
Design Thinking
Strategic Planning
Storytelling
UX Mentorship
Team Training
Accessible Design

UX Research & Design
Usability Testing
A/B Testing
Surveys
Interviews
HTML / CSS / JS
Journey Mapping
Persona Development
Competitive Analysis
Data Analysis
Card Sorting
Tree Testing
Focus Groups
Prototyping / Figma

Project Management

Process Improvement KPI Development Metrics Tracking Evaluation and Reporting Confluence / JIRA B2B and B2C